Guide to the Henry Leveke Kamphoefner Papers, 1924 - 1990 MC 00198
Special Collections Research Center
Henry Leveke Kamphoefner Papers
1924 - 1990
MC 00198
Special Collections Research Center
35.0 Linear feet
The Henry Leveke Kamphoefner Papers dates from 1924 to 1990 and includes correspondence, magazine articles, news clippings, speeches, photographs, architectural drawings, and artifacts. The collection documents Kamphoefner's professional life as an architect and as a professor and dean at North Carolina State University and other academic institutions. It also includes information about Kamphoefner's personal life.
Henry Leveke Kamphoefner was dean of the North Carolina State College (later North Carolina State University) School of Design, 1948-1973, and continued to teach architecture at North Carolina State Universtiy until 1979. Kamphoefner practiced architecture in Sioux City, Iowa, 1932-1936; was associate architect for the Rural Resettlement Administration in Washington, D.C., 1936-1937; and taught architecture at the University of Oklahoma, 1937-1948.
28 archival storage boxes, 37 flat files and 12 volumes
Kamphoefner, Henry Leveke, 1907-1990
Restrictions to Access
This collection is open for research; access requires at least 24 hours advance notice.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Henry Leveke Kamphoefner, July 10, 1987; Charles Larson, August 7, 1990; Caroline Carlton, North Carolina State University Design Library, August 9, 1990; Design School, Dean's Office, November 19, 1990; and Caroline Carlton, North Carolina State University Design Library, January 20, 1993.
Acquisitions Information
Gift of Henry Leveke Kamphoefner, July 10, 1987; Charles Larson, August 7, 1990; Caroline Carlton, North Carolina State University Design Library, August 9, 1990; Design School, Dean's Office, November 19, 1990; and Caroline Carlton, North Carolina State University Design Library, January 20, 1993.
Biographical Note
Henry Leveke Kamphoefner, the son of a Methodist preacher, was born in Des Moines, Iowa in 1907. He attended Morningside College in Sioux City, Iowa from 1924 to 1926 and graduated in 1930 from the University of Illinois with a Bachelor of Science degree in architecture. In 1931, he received a Master of Science degree in architecture from Columbia University, and in 1932, he received a Certificate in Architecture from the Beaux Arts Institute of Design in New York.
Kamphoefner returned to Sioux City in 1932 and privately practiced architecture there through 1936. From 1936 through 1937, he worked as an associate architect for the Rural Resettlement Administration in Washington, D.C. Kamphoefner then took a position as professor of architecture at the University of Oklahoma, where he remained through 1948. During his tenure there, he also worked as an architect for the United States Navy during the summers of 1938, 1939, and 1941. Kamphoefner was also a visiting professor at the University of Michigan during the summer of 1947. In 1948, Kamphoefner became the first dean of the North Carolina State College (later North Carolina State University) School of Design. He remained as dean until 1973, when he retired and was named dean emeritus. He continued teaching until 1979, when the mandatory retirement age of 72 was invoked by the university and Kamphoefner was required to leave. Following his retirement from North Carolina State, Kamphoefner became Distinguished Visiting Professor at Meredith College in Raleigh, where he remained from 1979-1981.
Kamphoefner's professional activities included acting as president of the Raleigh Council of Architects (1955-1956); as a member of the Board of Directors (1965), treasurer (1959-1963), director (1959-1967), and president (1963-1965) of the Association of Collegiate Schools of Architecture (ACSA); as a member of the Design Panel of Architects to the United States Navy (1964); and as National Endowment for the Humanities Humanist in Residence in Fayetteville, North Carolina (Fall 1977). Kamphoefner received several awards and honors for his professional work, including an honorary Doctorate of Fine Arts from Morningside College (1967); an honorary Doctorate of Laws from Ball State University (1972); an award in Joint Achievement for Lasting Achievement in Architectural Education (1977); and a North Carolina Award for Achievement in the Fine Arts (1978). His 1934 building, the Grandview Music Pavilion in Sioux City, Iowa, was selected by the Royal Institute of British Architects as one of "America's Outstanding Buildings of the Post-War Period."
Kamphoefner married Mabel C. Franchere on January 5, 1937. He died in Raleigh on February 14, 1990.
Scope and Content Note
The Henry Leveke Kamphoefner Papers documents the personal and professional life of Henry Kamphoefner. Included are materials relating to Kamphoefner's private architectural practice in Sioux City, Iowa; his tenure as professor at the School of Architecture at the University of Oklahoma; his tenure as Dean of the School of Design at North Carolina State University; and his activities after retirement at NCSU, at the University of North Carolina at Charlotte, and at Meredith College in Raleigh, North Carolina. The Professional Correspondence series is especially rich in documentation of all facets of his career, as Kamphoefner kept meticulous copies of his own letters as well as those received. Architectural drawings in the Oversized Materials series document his student work at the University of Illinois and at Columbia University, at his private practice in Iowa and on several other projects including his own residences in Norman, Oklahoma and Raleigh, North Carolina.
Organization of the Collection
The collection is organized into eight series: Professional Correspondence; Personal Correspondence; Administrative Materials; Speeches, Lectures and Publications; Reference Files; Photographs and Postcards; Artifacts and Memorabilia; and Oversized Materials.
Kamphoefner, Henry Leveke, 1907-1990; Meredith College (Raleigh, N.C.); North Carolina State College. School of Design--Administration.; North Carolina State University. School of Design--Faculty--History.; Architectural drawings; Architecture; Lecture notes; Letters (correspondence); Memorabilia; Postcards; Speeches
- Professional Correspondence, 1931-1989; 3.75 Linear feet; 7.5 archival boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  The Professional Correspondence series documents the career of Kamphoefner in private practice in Sioux City, Iowa, as professor at the University of Oklahoma, and as founding Dean of the School of Design at North Carolina State University. Kamphoefner's role in developing the School of Architecture at the University of Oklahoma is also well-documented. Further, his professional contacts nationwide are reflected in his correspondence during the formative years of the School of Design at North Carolina State College. The series also includes information regarding Kamphoefner's consulting work for various projects including city planning and acting as an expert witness in several lawsuits. There is a complete collection of letters of reference for Kamphoefner's appointment as Fellow in the American Institute of Architects as well as letters of reference he provided for other architects. The series also documents several architectural projects designed by Kamphoefner, including the award-winning Music Pavilion and Outdoor Theater at Grandview Park in Sioux City, Iowa (1934). Further, there is documentation on Kamphoefner's professional involvement with the American Institute of Architects (AIA) and the Association of Collegiate Schools of Architecture (ACSA). There is also correspondence relating to his activities in retirement, including teaching and travel. Correspondence relating to Kamphoefner's own residences in Norman, Oklahoma and Raleigh, North Carolina can be found in the Personal Correspondence series. The Professional Correspondence series is generally arranged first by subject and then chronologically.
  - Private Practice and Consulting
    - 1931-1933 (Box MC198.1, Folder 1)
    - 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1957-1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - [no date] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Private Practice, McEvare House
    - January 1952-August 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - September 1952-December 1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Consulting
    - Blumcraft of Pittsburgh, 1963-1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Chattanooga Housing Authority
      - 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Raleigh Civic Center Structure, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Columbia Mental Health Center, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Cooler v. Quail Hollow Condominium Association, 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Eastern Kentucky State College, 1961-1967 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Eola Park Bandshell, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Fraternity Housing Arbitration, North Carolina State University, 1959-1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - General Electric, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Hill and Knowlton, Incorporated, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Libbey Owens Ford Glass Company, 1945-1949 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Mercury Construction v. I.M. Pei, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Metropolitan Washington Board of Trade, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Mountlawn Memorial Park, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - National Building Museum, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Naval Design Panel, 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Odell v. City of Charlotte, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Par-Golf Driving Range, 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Polylok v. Romeo Guest, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Project Parkshell, Charlotte, 1965-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Tarboro High School, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - University of Alaska, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Wenger Manufacturing Company, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Professor of Architecture, University of Oklahoma
    - 1937-1941 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 1944 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - 1945 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - 1946 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Dean, School of Design, North Carolina State University
    - 1948-1954 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - 1958-1960 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Dean Emeritus, North Carolina State University
    - 1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - 1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - [no date] (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - University of North Carolina-Charlotte, 1973-1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Iredell County Humanist, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Visiting Distinguished Professor, Meredith College, 1979-1982 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fayetteville Humanist in Residence
    - 1977-1981 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Expenses, 1977-1981 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Programs, 1977-1981 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Fayetteville Data, 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Appointment Calendar, 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - News Clippings, 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - AIA, General Correspondence, 1972-1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - AIA College of Fellows
    - Kamphoefner Nomination References, 1954-1957 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - General Nomination References, 1947, 1970-1983 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - General Nomination References, 1984-1989 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - ACSA General Correspondence, 1961-1988 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - ACSA/AIA Joint Award
    - Letters of Support for Kamphoefner, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Kamphoefner Nomination, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Letters of Support for Kamphoefner, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Letters of Congratulation for Kamphoefner, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - American Civic and Planning Association, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Association, Columbia University, 1941, 1981-1987 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Personal Correspondence, 1930-1989; 1.5 Linear feet; 3 archival boxes
  This series includes Kamphoefner's personal correspondence with his friends and associates, chiefly other members of the architectural profession. Correspondence with family members and the correspondence of Kamphoefner's wife, Mabel, is contained in this series. Further, Kamphoefner's involvement with civic and charitable organizations is documented in this series. Also included is correspondence relating to Kamphoefner's own residences in Norman, Oklahoma and Raleigh, North Carolina. This group of materials documents the process of designing and building these two homes. Personal correspondence is arranged by subject and then chronologically.
  - Friends and Associates
    - 1930-1942 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 1947-1958 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - 1959-1967 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - 1968-1972 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - 1973-1980 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - 1981-1989 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - [no date] (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Greeting Cards, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Postcards, 1938-1986, [no date] (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Viall Family, 1967-1982 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Taylor Family, 1977-1988 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Family
    - 1935, 1945-1953 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - 1964-1979 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - 1983-1989 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - [no date] (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Thomas Larson Family, 1946, 1969-1989 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Charles Larson Family, 1959-1979 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Mabel Kamphoefner Correspondence
    - 1948-1987 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Hoyte Franchere, 1946-1973 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Z. Mrowzynska, 1959-1967 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Greeting Cards, [no date] (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - [no date] (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Civic and Charitable Organizations
    - Meredith College, 1980-1984 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - University of North Carolina-Charlotte, 1983-1986 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - North Carolina State University, 1974-1987 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - School of Design/North Carolina AIA, 1973-1989 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Kamphoefner Award Recipients, 1973-1989 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Kamphoefner Fund, Legal Correspondence, 1981-1987 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Fine Arts Council, 1959-1964 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - North Carolina Awards, 1977-1988 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Politics, 1949-1989 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1987 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Residence at Norman, Oklahoma, 1941-1948, 1956, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Residence at Raleigh, North Carolina
    - Construction, 1948-1979 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Furnishings, 1949-1983 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Publications and Inquiries, 1951-1977 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Administrative Materials, 1950-1989; 1.0 linear foot; 2 archival boxes
  This series contains documents, news clippings, memoranda, programs, and reports relating to various professional positions held by Kamphoefner. However, the bulk of the records regarding his position in the North Carolina State University Design School are part of the University Archives at NC State. Also included are references made and reviewed by Kamphoefner for nominations for fellowships in the American Institute of Architects. The series is arranged by subject.
  - University of Oklahoma
    - 1940-1946 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Campus Planning, 1942-1946 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Architectural Survey of University College, c. 1942 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - National Architectural Accrediting Board (NAAB), 1947 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - News Clippings, [no date] (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - School of Design, North Carolina State University
    - 1950, 1958, 1973-1988 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - NAAB, 1970s-1980s (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Golden Section, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Lecture Programs and Publications, 1980s (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970s, 1980s (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Meredith College, 1979-1982 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Organizations
    - AIA College of Fellows, Kamphoefner Nomination, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - AIA Miscellaneous Reports, 1947, 1953, 1968, 1972-1988 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - AIA College of Fellows, Brian Shawcroft Nomination, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - AIA College of Fellows, Brian Shawcroft Nomination, Photographic Portfolio, [no date] (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - AIA College of Fellows, Digests of Achievement and References, 1973-1990 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - AIA North Carolina Chapter, Miscellaneous Newsletters, 1974-1986 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - ACSA/AIA Joint Award for Lasting Achievement, Nominations, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - ACSA Miscellaneous Newsletters, 1973, 1976-1977, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Architectural Registration Boards, 1963-1972, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Friends of the Gallery, NC State, Meeting Minutes, 1982-1989 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Friends of the Gallery, NC State, By-laws, Reports Rosters, 1984-1987 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Friends of the Gallery, NC State, Miscellaneous Programs and Invitations, [no date] (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Kamphoefner Fund, Miscellaneous Materials, 1981-1983 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - North Carolina Design Foundation, Memoranda of Understanding, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - North Carolina Design Foundation, Miscellaneous Memoranda and Reports, 1981-1989 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Raleigh Chamber of Commerce, 1968-1972 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Spectra School, Board of Advisors, 1982-1985 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Speeches, Lectures, and Publications, 1946-1984; 1.25 Linear feet; 2.5 archival boxes
  This series reflects Kamphoefner's devotion to modern design. Many of his speeches and lectures are controversial in their criticism of traditional architecture and responses to these statements and opinions are well-documented in the Professional Correspondence series. Lectures also include research and preparation for his classes. Publications contain information relating to his writing and his architectural projects, especially his residences in Norman, Oklahoma and Raleigh, North Carolina.
  - Speeches
    - "What is Modern Architecture?", 1946 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - "Architectural Education and Church Architecture,", 1947 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - American Association of University Women (AAUW), 1948 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - "Contemporary Architecture and the Southern Tradition,", 1948 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - "Contemporary Architecture and the Church,", 1956 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Statement about Raleigh Architecture, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - ACSA, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - "Observations on the Roots of Contemporary Architecture,", 1976 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Clemson University, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - "Windows of St. Luke's,", 1984 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Interview with Charles Kahn, [no date] (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Notes from a Speech in Chapel Hill, [no date] (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Lectures
    - University of Oklahoma, 1941-1948 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Architecture 9, 1943-1948 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Architecture 9, ca. 1948 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Architecture 10, 1944-1948 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Architecture 180, [no date] (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Architecture 245, 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Architecture 321, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Design 542, 531, 1954-1955 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Design 541, 1954-1979 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Art 200, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Design 211, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Design 122, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Architecture 421, 1974-1976 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Design 441, Slide List, [no date] (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Design 441, 1977-1984 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Architecture 499, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Art 941, Meredith College, 1979-1980 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Publications
    - University of Oklahoma, 1940-1946, [no date] (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - North Carolina State University, 1962, [no date] (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Book Reviews, 1961-1962, [no date] (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Letters to the Editor, 1947-1969 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Letters to the Editor, 1981-1987 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Statement of Sales from Cities are Abnormal, 1947-1967 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - "Acoustics of Music Shells", 1941 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Articles, 1944-1947 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Articles, 1949, 1962, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Music Pavilion and Outdoor Theater at Grandview Park, 1934-1975, [no date] (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Music Pavilion at Ft. Dodge, 1937, [no date] (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Campus of the University of Oklahoma, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Residence at Norman, Oklahoma, 1942, 1945, [no date] (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Residence at Raleigh, North Carolina, 1951-1957, 1973, [no date] (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Reference Files, 1.5 Linear feet; 3 archival boxes
  This series contains news clippings, articles, and other material documenting Kamphoefner's interest or association with well-known figures in architecture and design. Included are projects, buildings and ideas in design and architectural education. A subseries of project specifications for early Kamphoefner projects (1932-1947) is also included. The series is arranged by subject.
  - Miscellaneous Resumes (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Batchelor, Peter (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Belluschi, Pietro (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Breuer, Marcel (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Fuller, Buckminster (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Burns, Robert (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Harris, Harwell (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Johnson, Philip (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Kermacy, Martin (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Langhorst, Lois (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Manning, Isaac (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Mies van der Rohe, Ludwig (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Neutra, Richard (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Pei, I.M. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Rudolph, Paul (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Saarinen, Eero (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Sappenfield, Charles (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Williams, F. Carter (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Wright, Frank Lloyd [File 1 of 2] (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Wright, Frank Lloyd [File 2 of 2] (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Planning Man's Physical Environment, Conference in Princeton, New Jersey, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Architectural Competitions, 1933-1947 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Beaux Arts Institute of Design, 1941-1944 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Beaux Arts Institute of Design, 1945-1949 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Tear Sheets, Architectural Forum, Architectural Record, Pencil Points, 1933-1948 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, Architectural Education (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, Buildings (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, Materials and Supplies (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Architectural Planning (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - News Clippings
    - General Architecture (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - North Carolina Museum of Art (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - School of Design, North Carolina State University (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Photographs and Postcards, 1.75 Linear feet; 3.5 archival boxes